Debashish Sahu

Senior Interaction Designer, 4.5 yrs. (Design) & 3.5 yrs. (Development)

- www.debashishsahu.co.in
- debashishsahu@outlook.com
- +91-7406891234

Summary

A keen designer with a strong passion for usability, with an eye for visual consistency, and a knack for reducing the complex to the bare essentials. Designing experience in B2B and B2C markets and with specific knowledge in Retail, BSFI, Travel and Healthcare domains. Ability to lead and contribute towards all the phases of design lifecycle for software, digital products & services.

Education

December 2013

National Institute of Design

PGDPD, New Media Design Ahmedabad, Gujarat Graduated The New Media Design

Programme is trans-disciplinary in nature, applying and integrating knowledge from various disciplines. In this sense, it is a unique combination of design, art, science and technology.

July 2007

Lingaya's Institute of Mgmt. and Technology

B.E., Computer Science
Graduated
Completed B.E., Computer
Science from Lingaya's Institute of
Technology affiliated to Maharishi
Dayanand University, Rohtak.

Employment History

Pramati Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

December 2015 - Present Hyderabad, Telangana

Mindtree Ltd.

November 2013 - December 2015 Bengaluru, Karnataka

Nagarro Softwares & Pvt. Ltd.

August 2010 - April 2011 Gurugram, Haryana Senior Interaction Designer (Design Lead)

Sr. Designer & Design Lead in Imaginea Design Labs

As a Sr. Interaction Designer, a major portion of my work involves coming up with new and best experiences for the varied software or digital products in the Design Labs and leading from the front.

User Experience Designer

Designer UX/IxD in Digital & RnD Lab

Worked as Interaction
Designer/User Experience
Designer in a co-innovation lab
called The Digital Pumpkin.
The Digital Pumpkin was a CoE of
the upcoming technology be it
Tangible Media, IoT, gestures
based devices, AR/VR etc. the
idea was to create a working
showcase of products and
solutions which could link
experience, end-users and
business together.

Senior Software Engineer, MDG

Design and Development of Sharepoint Web Portals

Worked as a Senior Software Engineer, Member Delivery Group in developing Web based applications in Microsoft Technologies in MOSS 2007 and SharePoint Server 2010.

Languages

English: Fluent Hindi: Fluent

Oriya: Conversational

L&T Infotech

November 2008 - April 2010 Navi Mumbai, Maharashtra

Software Engineer

Design and Development of Sharepoint Web Portals

Worked as a Software Engineer in the Team which worked exclusively

on the various internet and

intranet webportals for Viacom Inc.

& MTV.

Hobbies & Interests

Game Design & Creation, IoT & Tagible Media, Programming, Computer Games & New Media Arts

Professional Skills

User Research:
User Experience Design:
Advanced
User Personas:
Intermediate
Storyboards:
Advanced
Wireframes:
Expert
Usability Testing:
Visual Design:
Intermediate